<!-- DRAFT appcast <item> for v1.6.0 — NOT live. Parked here because appcast.xml on `main`
     IS the production Sparkle feed (SUFeedURL points at the raw GitHub file): pushing this
     item with placeholders made every installed 1.5.5 offer a broken update (2026-07-12).

     At release cut:
     1. Build + export the Release .app, create syncthingStatus-v1.6.0.dmg
     2. sign_update syncthingStatus-v1.6.0.dmg  → paste output into sparkle:edSignature
     3. Set length="" to the DMG's byte size (stat -f%z syncthingStatus-v1.6.0.dmg)
     4. Set pubDate to the actual release date/time
     5. Create the v1.6.0 GitHub release + upload the DMG so the enclosure URL resolves
     6. ONLY THEN move this <item> to the top of appcast.xml's <channel> and push. -->
<item>
    <title>Version 1.6.0</title>
    <description><![CDATA[
        <h2>What's New in Version 1.6.0</h2>
        <h3>New</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>Stuck-deletion detection &amp; cleanup</strong> &mdash; when Syncthing can't finish deleting a file, the folder stays "Out of sync" indefinitely. syncthingStatus now detects this, flags it with an amber alert row in the popover, and opens a dedicated cleanup window that lists every stuck item, lets you <strong>Reveal</strong> each one in Finder, and &mdash; once you grant folder access &mdash; safely removes the leftovers and rescans so the folder goes green again.</li>
            <li><strong>Sandbox-safe folder access</strong> &mdash; the cleanup flow requests access to only the affected folder via the standard macOS open panel and remembers it with a security-scoped bookmark. No Full Disk Access required.</li>
            <li><strong>Inline Rescan button</strong> on the out-of-sync folder row &mdash; one-click rescan without opening the context menu.</li>
            <li><strong>Diagnostic export</strong> &mdash; one-click export of the app's recent logs from Settings for bug reports. Sandbox-clean; nothing is written to disk during normal use.</li>
            <li><strong>Versions at a glance</strong> &mdash; the popover's Local Device row shows the app and running Syncthing versions, and the About panel reports the connected Syncthing version.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>Bug Fixes</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>No more false "Disconnected" flash</strong> &mdash; refreshing while another refresh was in flight (e.g. right after changing a setting) could briefly flip the icon to red. A superseded refresh is now ignored instead of being reported as a disconnection.</li>
            <li><strong>Reliable on non-English systems</strong> &mdash; internal cancellation checks no longer depend on English error text, so transient errors no longer leak to the UI on localized macOS installs.</li>
            <li><strong>Launch at Login actually works</strong> &mdash; the Settings toggle had never registered the app with macOS. Flipping it on now really adds syncthingStatus to System Settings &rarr; Login Items.</li>
            <li><strong>Pause/Resume no longer fails silently</strong> &mdash; if pausing or resuming a device or folder doesn't reach Syncthing, the app now shows the error instead of doing nothing.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>
    <pubDate>REPLACE_ME_PUBDATE</pubDate>
    <enclosure
        url="https://github.com/Xpycode/syncthingStatus/releases/download/v1.6.0/syncthingStatus-v1.6.0.dmg"
        sparkle:version="162"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="1.6.0"
        length="REPLACE_ME_LENGTH"
        type="application/octet-stream"
        sparkle:edSignature="REPLACE_ME_EDSIGNATURE"
    />
    <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.5</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
</item>
